Guide to the Betty Castor Papers
Betty Castor Papers 1962-1999
C08
Castor, Betty, 1940 -
12.00
10 boxes
USF Tampa Library - Special Digital Collections 4202 East Fowler Ave. LIB122 Tampa, FL, 33620-5400 URL: http://www.lib.usf.edu/ Email: rbernard@usf.edu Phone: 813-974-1622 Fax: 813-396-9006
Other Information: ready Additional information may be found at http://usfldc:U29-00034-C08
Biographical Information:
Elizabeth “Betty” Bowe Castor-Bell was born to Irish immigrants on May 11, 1941. A native of Glassboro, New Jersey, Castor moved to Florida in 1966, where she became a politician, a proponent of educational causes, and the first female president of the University of South Florida.
Castor’s career has spanned continents, bridged social and political gaps, and afforded numerous awards, honors and appointments. A brief overview of Castor’s educational and political career is as follows:
- Bachelor of Arts, Education (Glassboro State College, New Jersey-- renamed to Rowan College)
- Master of Arts, Education (University of Miami, Florida)
- Hillsborough County Board of Commissioners, 1972-1976 (Chair, 1975-1976)
- Senator, State of Florida (1976-1978)
- Senator, State of Florida, representing Hillsborough, Pinellas and Pasco Counties (1982-1986)
- Florida Commission of Education (1986-1993)
- President, University of South Florida (1994-1999)
- President, National Board of Professional Teaching Standards (1999-)
In accordance, Betty Castor’s most acknowledged achievements include: an Honorary Doctorate from the University of South Florida (2000); the Judeo-Christian Health Clinic’s 1994 Humanitarian Award; recognition as the 1986 Legislator of the Year; the “Class of ‘56” distinction, which the University of South Florida bestows upon non-graduates who have rendered outstanding service to USF and to the community; and the honor of being one of the youngest presidents of Tampa’s League of Women Voters.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Personal Name:
Castor, Betty
Administrative Information
Acquisition Information:
Donation.
Conditions Governing Access:
None. The contents of this collection may be subject to copyright. Visit the United States Copyright Offices website at http://www.copyright.gov/ for more information.
Arrangement of Materials:
Alphabetically by subject within series.
Scope and Contents
The bulk of this collection consists of printed materials, such as newspaper clippings and publications, documenting Castor’s political career. Also accompanying the papers are numerous awards and plaques presented to Castor for her service to the citizens of Florida. In August 2008, action was taken to re-assess and weed the plaques and awards. Only those items that were considered relative to the history of the University of South Florida or of significance to Betty Castor’s career were retained. A CD (compact disc) containing pictures of the plaques and trophies is included, and an itemized list has been added to Castors donor file.
Materials compromising the Betty Castor papers do not include her official USF presidential papers, which are a part of the University Archives and are currently (2007) in remote storage.
Detailed List of Contents
- Articles – 1976-1997, id5565 (Box 1)
  - Articles 1976-1993, id5566 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles 1994-1995, id5567 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Articles 1995-1997, id5568 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bell, Samuel Paris ~ Florida State Division of Elections, id5569 (Box 2)
  - Bell, Samuel Paris, id5570 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Information, id5571 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Elections, id5572 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, id5573 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Scope and Contents
    Documents regarding the proposal and ratification of the 27thamendment and its affect on other laws, regulations, etc.
  - Florida Commission on Education., id5574 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Florida State Cabinet, id5575 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Florida State Division of Elections, id5576 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Gubernatorial Race ~ Women, id5577 (Box 3)
  - Gubernatorial Race-1978, id5578 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Running mate of Lt. Governor Jim Williams.
  - Hillsborough County Anti-Rape Organizations, id5579 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Hillsborough County Board of Commissioners, id5580 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Hillsborough County Growth, id5581 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Interviews, id5582 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Jamerson, Rep. Doug “Tim”, id5583 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, id5584 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Includes newspaper clippings and journal articles, committee meeting information, limited correspondence.
  - National Board of Professional Teaching Standards, id5585 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, id5586 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Speeches, id5587 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - University Club, id5588 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Women, id5589 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Newspaper articles concerning the social and political roles of women.
- Advancement ~ Presidential Resignation, id5590 (Box 4)
  - Advancement, id5591 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Athletics, id5592 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Budget, id5593 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Ceremonies and Events, id5594 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Faculty and Staff, id5595 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Relations, id5596 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Free Speech, id5597 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Inauguration, id5598 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Libraries, id5599 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Lifsey House, id5600 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, id5601 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Presidency- Articles, id5602 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Presidency- Editorials, id5603 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Presidential Appointment, id5604 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Presidential Campaign- Opposition, id5605 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Presidential Campaign-Support, id5606 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Presidential Papers, id5607 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Presidential Race, id5608 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Presidential Resignation, id5609 (Box 4, Folder 19)